Nicholas Patten

Flat 4, 18 Blackall Road, Exeter, Devon, United Kingdom, EX4 4HE 07790200756, nicholaspatten92@gmail.com

Profile

Dev-Ops engineer with over two years of experience in the software industry. Capable of working as part of a team, or independently to fulfill the role. Willing to learn from, and teach others in order to improve delivery of the product.

Experience

- Languages:

Groovy (Gradle & Jenkins DSL), Java, Javascript, Bash, C

- Frameworks:

Grails, Ruby on Rails, Spring

- Database & Database Related:

Oracle, SQL, Hibernate, JPA, Data-Modeling

- Build Automation & Continuous Integration:

Maven, Gradle, Jenkins, Artifactory

- Development & Testing Tools:

JUnit, Powermockito, archaius, Tomcat

- IDE's & Text Editors:

Eclipse/STS, NetBeans, Atom, Kate, VIM

- Version Control:

Git, Mercurial

- Markup, Stylesheet and Template Engines:

XHTML, JSON, CSS, XML, Freemarker, LATEX

- OS:

Windows, Mac OSX, Various Linux distributions e.g. Debian, CentOS/Redhat, CoreOs

Employment

Present

2014 - 17 CMS Release Manager, Mirada Exeter

Responsible for the managerial and development aspects of providing releases of the company's CMS product to various environments to support business continuity.

The management side of this role involves communicating with other teams to ensure that their schedules are on time for the next release and working to resolve any blockers that they may encounter. This requires me to spend a lot of time with staff, working through their build issues, scheduling problems and discussing best implementation methods for designing their service changes.

Very hands on with development, focusing on designing and implementing build processes. This is often programmatically declared using languages such as groovy and bash, which are normally accompanied by Jenkins' jobs. Maintenance and improvement of these processes and scripts are core to the continuous delivery of the product. Often in technical meetings, with various levels of management, around how best to improve our processes and the benefits of the proposed solutions.

Operational tasks are occasionally required as issues arise in deployment environments, which need to be taken care of before the install process can continue. Acquired good experience with command line and managing Linux based services such as solr, rabbitmq, oracle database, sshd and more. Currently involved in a project, migrating a bricks and mortar system to a cloud-based container system.

Past

2013 - 13 National Museum, Cardiff

Short period of work experience, assisting a senior network supervisor. Various skills gained, including managing network cables, cabinets and HP server blades.

2011 - 11 **Oxfam, Cardiff**

Charity work as a shop floor assistant and stock organiser. Gained team working skills and customer service experience.

2008 - 08 Maplin's Electronics, Cardiff

Work experience as a shop floor assistant. Gained high-quality team working and customer service skills.

Education

2011 - 14 Aberystwyth University; Computer Science BSc Hons:

Major Project; Ms. Pac-Man Artificial Intelligence Software Controller:

Researched and developed an autonomous software controller for the video game, Ms Pac-Man game

Modules:

C++, C And Java Programming Paradigms

C And Unix Programming

Concepts in Programming

Agile Methodologies

Software Development Life-cycle

Developing Internet Based Applications

Modelling Persistent Data

Computing Mathematics

2009 - 10 St David's Catholic College; GCE A Level:

Computing, Film Studies, Welsh Baccalaureate

2004 - 09 St Teilo's CIW High School; GCSEs:

Nine GCSE's, including: IT (A), DT: Systems and Control (B), English Lang & Lit (C), Maths (C), Science (C)

Interests

Fascinated by ever moving technology, always researching embracing the next big thing. Avid video game enthusiast, across multiple platforms. Very sociable and approachable, always up for a company outing and getting to know other members of staff.

Referees

References available on request